

#### **SHRAY RAWAT**

Address: 304, Sri Mitra Spring Valley, Phone: +91-8861374821

Kaikondrahalli lake trail , Sarjapur Road, Email: <a href="mailto:shrayrawat@gmail.com">shrayrawat@gmail.com</a>

Bangalore - 560035

## **Summary**

Software engineer with 4.7 yrs experience in product development. Love to code, keen on learning designing and software architecture and new programming paradigms. I want to be associated with a leading global organization where my qualifications, skills and potential can be effectively utilized and improved to achieve expertise in my field.

## **Skills Summary**

- Java
- Elastic Search
- Apache Kafka
- Aerospike
- Eclipse
- Selenium
- GIT/STASH
- Springs

- Agile Methodology
- Data Structures/Algorithms

#### **Major Demonstrated Strengths**

- Handled major backend components in various projects.
- Responsibility includes alignment with multiple verticals, component owners and product owners and delivering the desired quality of features on time. Along with this self involvement in designing, coding and mentoring of freshers at the same time.
- Part of the main prototyping team in the department that is responsible for doing POC's that will help the existing projects to become more efficient and also prototyping innovative ideas.
- Awarded three times in company for mentoring the new joiners and ramping up them fast so that they can start contributing towards the project as soon as possible.
- Demonstrated extensive problem solving skills in providing solutions to various project related issues.
- Result oriented and self-driven professional skilled with working in a dual role of development and production support.
- Acted as a transversal resource in the department by working in different projects simultaneously.

#### **Work History**

April 2016 -present : Senior Software Engineer

**Company - Snapdeal** 

**Project Description:** Design, Architecture, development of highly scalable system for seller details. Using this system we can monitor the quality issues and other issues at real-time and take appropriate disruptive or reactive action on that seller order or seller, and hence ensuring



good quality from next time onwards for providing the consumer a better experience than before.

Technology: Core Java, MySql, Kafka, Drools, Rest web-service, Spring 4(Spring MVC), Maven

3.0, Tomcat server for Deployment.

Tools: Eclipse as the java development tool.

#### May 2015 - March 2016 : Software Engineer II

**Company:Snapdeal** 

**Project Description:** Developed a highly scalable system for customer reviews and ratings provisioning and query. The architecture involved multiple technologies including the NOSql, Event Bus and many other sub systems.

Technology: Core Java, Cassandra 2.1.3, Elastic Search, Kafka, Aerospike, Rest web-service, Spring3(Spring MVC), Maven 3.0, MySQL, Apache and Tomcat server for Deployment.

# June 2012 – May 2015 : Senior Software Engineer Company – Amadeus Software Labs India Pvt. Ltd. Company Description:

Amadeus IT Group was a client for **Ness Technologies** working on **Built Operate Transfer model**. So it got separated from Ness technologies in 2012 to form its own Indian subsidiary known as Amadeus Software Labs India Pvt.Ltd.

**Project Description:** Worked in two projects. **Massive Computation Quality Monitoring.** MCQM was concerned with analyzing the Amadeus data caching quality by comparing the flight prices in cache every 15 minutes with the actual fare products that will return the current flight prices. The project was made to be highly scalable and able to run 24\*7.

**Fares Analysis**: This was the second project. The client needed a tool for auditing the fare filing done in regards to the filing contract they agreed with their customer. Moreover, the competition leads to constant updates of Airline client prices that they offer; so they need monitoring tools to help them to have a comprehensive view of it.

#### **Environment:**

Database: MYSQL, Migrating to NOSQL in future.

Operating System : Windows, Unix

Technology: J2SE, J2EE, GWT, Selenium, JMS Queues

Tools: Internal Release Integration tools, IBM purify, SOAP-UI, Weblogic

Practice: Agile methodology

#### Responsibility:

- Involved in designing of major components for MCQM.
- Upgrading the design in the second phase of the project to make it easier to implement different customers and products in less time.
- Automating the statistics collection to remove the manual monitoring of production logs for MCOM.
- Implementing and delivering the changes required ASAP by the client during product demo by marketing team. This helped to secure a contract for the Fares Analysis product.
- Giving Knowledge Transfer Sessions for new members.



Java SE 6 Programmer

- Functional testing support and Production support.
- Accessing the resource usage so as to come up with the capacity analysis for the production machines

## November 2011-June2012: Software Engineer Trainee Company – Ness Technologies Customer – Amadeus IT group Customer Description:

Amadeus IT Group is a transaction processor for the global travel and tourism industry. The company is structured around two key related areas - its global distribution system and its IT.

**Project Description:** Competition monitoring is mainly extracting the data from the various inhouse products and airline websites for some trip scenarios (Origin, destination, Dep.Date, Return Date) so that a comparison can be done for the correct market position in offering the best recommendations for the trip scenarios.

#### **Environment:**

Database: MySql

Operating System: Windows, Unix

Technology: J2SE, GWT, Spring, Selenium, HMA-VPN Tools: Internal Release Integration Tools, IBM purify

Practice: Agile methodology

#### **Responsibility:**

- Involved in developing the framework to do automated extraction from different white listed client websites.
- Giving Knowledge Transfer Sessions for new members.
- Functional testing support.
- Doing POC's for new technologies and design approaches to make project more efficient.

#### **Awards**

Amadeus Spot Award – Awarded 2 times for mentoring and for good quality deliverables. Snapdeal Pat on the Back award.

#### Certifications

Oracle Certified Java SE6 Programmer.

#### **Employment History**

Nov 2011 to June 2012 – Ness Technologies(Client:Amadeus IT Group. Transferred to Amadeus)

June 2012 to May 2015 – Amadeus Software Labs. India Pvt. Ltd.

May 2015 to present - Snapdeal



# **Education**

Class	Board / University	Marks	Year Of Passing
B-TECH, Computer Science Engineering	Rajasthan Technical University	70.1	2011
XII <sup>th</sup>	CBSE	83	2007
$X^{th}$	CBSE	85	2005